Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Reborn from the Ashes]
[ولدت من الرماد]
[Episode 17]
[الحلقة 17]
Those who defy
أولئك الذين يتحدون
will die.
يريد ذلك.
I am the Governor of Yunzhou City.
أنا حاكم مدينة يونتشو.
Even if you are the crown prince of Prince Zhenbei,
حتى لو كنت ولي عهد الأمير تشنبي،
there must be a reason to arrest me.
لا بد من وجود سبب لاعتقالي.
Were you injured?
هل تعرضت لإصابة؟
It's nothing.
لا شئ.
Governor Su, you abused your position,
يا حاكم سو، لقد أسأت استخدام منصبك.
colluding in corruption,
التواطؤ في الفساد،
and hoarding black gunpowder.
وتخزين البارود الأسود.
Your crimes are unforgivable.
جرائمك لا تغتفر.
Take him away.
خذوه بعيداً.
You really have a silver tongue.
لديك لسان فصيح حقاً.
You slander me without any proof.
أنت تشوه سمعتي دون أي دليل.
I have proof.
لدي دليل.
Su Guang,
سو قوانغ,
all these years,
طوال هذه السنوات،
you've been using me to transport black gunpowder.
لقد كنت تستخدمني لنقل البارود الأسود.
Uncle,
عم،
what brings you here?
ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
Qingran,
كينغران،
take these chestnut pastries.
خذ هذه المعجنات المصنوعة من الكستناء.
You came all this way
لقد أتيت من كل هذه المسافة
just to bring me chestnut pastries?
هل تريد فقط أن تحضر لي معجنات الكستناء؟
I'm leaving tonight.
سأغادر الليلة.
I don't know when I'll return.
لا أعرف متى سأعود.
I don't know what's wrong with Su Guang;
لا أعرف ما المشكلة مع سو غوانغ؛
he suddenly told me to travel overnight
فجأة طلب مني أن أسافر طوال الليل
to deliver a batch of goods.
لتسليم دفعة من البضائع.
Goods?
بضائع؟
Black gunpowder?
البارود الأسود؟
I've never seen it before.
لم أره من قبل.
Are you transporting black gunpowder yourself,
هل تقوم بنقل البارود الأسود بنفسك؟
trying to frame me?
هل تحاولون تلفيق تهمة لي؟
Su Guang,
سو قوانغ,
you're so cruel.
أنت قاسٍ للغاية.
Even with death approaching, you still blame me.
حتى مع اقتراب الموت، ما زلت تلومني.
Fine.
بخير.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
this is the list Su Guang hid among the goods.
هذه هي القائمة التي أخفاها سو غوانغ بين البضائع.
You can verify the handwriting.
يمكنك التحقق من خط اليد.
Su Guang, you have committed treason for personal gain.
سو غوانغ، لقد ارتكبت الخيانة العظمى لتحقيق مكاسب شخصية.
You actually sold gunpowder to the enemy state.
لقد بعتَ البارود بالفعل للدولة المعادية.
You are not worthy of being the governor.
أنت لا تستحق أن تكون حاكماً.
[The gunpowder is foreign] The evidence is clear now.
[البارود أجنبي] الأدلة واضحة الآن.
What explanation do you still have?
ما هو التفسير الذي لا يزال لديك؟
Take him away.
خذوه بعيداً.
Yes.
نعم.
Go.
يذهب.
Where did the gunpowder come from?
من أين أتى البارود؟
Speak.
يتكلم.
Hurry up and speak.
أسرع وتكلم.
Spare me!
ارحمني!
I'll tell you.
سأخبرك.
I'll say everything.
سأقول كل شئ.
Speak.
يتكلم.
I bought all the gunpowder from the black market.
اشتريت كل البارود من السوق السوداء.
Was the poison used to kill the Qilin Army
هل تم استخدام السم لقتل جيش الكيلين؟
also bought from the black market?
هل تم شراؤه أيضاً من السوق السوداء؟
The Prince already told you?
هل أخبرك الأمير بذلك بالفعل؟
Where is the account book?
أين دفتر الحسابات؟
Wanyan Lie knows the account book wasn't destroyed.
يعلم وانيان لي أن دفتر الحسابات لم يُدمر.
What account book?
أي دفتر حسابات؟
I don't know what you're talking about.
لا أعرف عما تتحدث.
My Lord.
سيدي.
You're the one who killed the Qilin Army.
أنت من قتل جيش الكيلين.
You're also the one who caused General Xiao Zhan's death.
أنت أيضاً من تسبب في وفاة الجنرال شياو زان.
Will you confess or not?
هل ستعترف أم لا؟
Wanyan Jin,
وانيان جين,
you don't dare kill me.
لا تجرؤ على قتلي.
Do you really think I'm afraid to kill you?
هل تعتقد حقاً أنني أخشى قتلك؟
My Lord,
سيدي
we can't kill him.
لا يمكننا قتله.
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
I know nothing at all.
لا أعرف شيئاً على الإطلاق.
My Lord.
سيدي.
Is that all then?
هل هذا كل شيء إذن؟
The account book is Su Guang's only safeguard.
يُعد دفتر الحسابات الضمانة الوحيدة لسو غوانغ .
That old fox won't reveal it so easily.
لن يكشف ذلك الثعلب العجوز الأمر بهذه السهولة.
Think of another way.
فكر في طريقة أخرى.
Yes.
نعم.
What's the status of Su Guang's case?
ما هو وضع قضية سو غوانغ؟
Has he confessed to anything?
هل اعترف بأي شيء؟
He refuses to say a word.
يرفض أن ينطق بكلمة واحدة.
This case is closed today.
تم إغلاق هذه القضية اليوم.
You don't need to waste any more time on him.
لا داعي لإضاعة المزيد من الوقت معه.
I understand, Father.
انا أفهم يا أبي.
You can go.
يمكنك الذهاب.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Su Guang is a key player in the case of the Qilin Army.
يُعد سو غوانغ لاعباً رئيسياً في قضية جيش الكيلين.
If he is executed without any confession,
إذا تم إعدامه دون أي اعتراف،
I won't be able to expose Wanyan Lie's crimes
لن أتمكن من فضح جرائم وانيان لي
and personally send him to the execution block,
وأرسله شخصياً إلى منصة الإعدام،
to avenge the soldiers of the Qilin Army.
للانتقام لجنود جيش الكيلين.
My Lord,
سيدي
we finally captured Su Guang,
لقد تمكنا أخيراً من القبض على سو غوانغ،
but still haven't gotten any useful information from him.
لكنني لم أحصل منه على أي معلومات مفيدة حتى الآن.
Are we really going to execute him so easily?
هل سنعدمه بهذه السهولة حقاً؟
Qi...
تشي...
Now that Su Guang is imprisoned,
والآن بعد سجن سو غوانغ،
the account book that can prove my father's innocence remains missing.
لا يزال دفتر الحسابات الذي يمكن أن يثبت براءة والدي مفقوداً.
Qingran,
كينغران،
rest assured.
اطمئن، لا تشغل بالك.
I will ask my father to plead for you.
سأطلب من والدي أن يتوسط من أجلك.
Thank you for your concern.
شكراً لاهتمامكم.
But,
لكن،
you should go comfort Feiyi instead.
يجب عليك أن تذهب لمواساة فييي بدلاً من ذلك.
Don't get me wrong.
لا تفهمني خطأً.
Su Feiyi and I
سو فيي وأنا
are just friends.
هم مجرد أصدقاء.
What's there to misunderstand?
ما الذي قد يُساء فهمه؟
Whether you two are close or not is none of my business.
سواء كنتما مقربين أم لا، فهذا ليس من شأني.
You come to my courtyard every day.
تأتي إلى فناء منزلي كل يوم.
It seems
يبدو
those without official duties have plenty of free time.
أولئك الذين لا يقومون بمهام رسمية لديهم الكثير من وقت الفراغ.
You are overwhelmed with affairs,
أنت غارق في شؤونك،
and I was worried Qingran would grieve alone,
وكنت قلقة من أن تحزن تشينغران وحدها،
so I came over to comfort her.
لذا ذهبت لأواسيها.
Do you think she even notices you?
هل تعتقد أنها حتى تلاحظك؟
Qi,
تشي،
it's better for you to focus on recovering.
من الأفضل لك أن تركز على التعافي.
Don't dwell on things you shouldn't.
لا تُطِل التفكير في أمور لا ينبغي لك التفكير فيها.
Don't even look
لا تنظر حتى
at what doesn't belong to you.
فيما لا يخصك.
Honey,
عسل،
you really do attract romantic troubles.
أنت حقاً تجذب المشاكل العاطفية.
But,
لكن،
they're all bad relationships.
جميعها علاقات سيئة.
It's all because I was born with natural beauty
كل ذلك لأنني وُلدت بجمال طبيعي
and a face like the moon among flowers.
ووجه كالقمر بين الزهور.
You must keep a close watch.
يجب عليك أن تراقب عن كثب.
Honey,
عسل،
you do not need my protection.
لست بحاجة لحمايتي.
Anyone who messes with you will regret it.
أي شخص يعبث معك سيندم على ذلك.
It's fine you understand.
لا بأس، أنت تفهم.
Su Guang is already imprisoned.
سو غوانغ مسجون بالفعل.
What do you plan to do next?
ماذا تخطط للقيام به بعد ذلك؟
So,
لذا،
I come here
أنا آتي إلى هنا
to ask you to let you see Su Guang.
أن أطلب منك أن تسمح لك برؤية سو غوانغ.
Can I?
هل يمكنني؟
You're begging me?
أنت تتوسل إلي؟
Hmm.
همم.
Then show
ثم أظهر
a more sincere attitude.
موقف أكثر صدقاً.
Please, I'm begging you.
من فضلك، أنا أتوسل إليك.
Please, please.
أرجوك، أرجوك.
Qi,
تشي،
I have no home now.
ليس لدي منزل الآن.
Everything from the Su Family has been confiscated.
تمت مصادرة كل شيء يخص عائلة سو .
I only have you now.
ليس لدي سواك الآن.
Back then when I told you
في ذلك الوقت عندما أخبرتك
that I was left all alone, what did you do?
لقد تُركت وحيداً تماماً، ماذا فعلت؟
You disliked that I am often sick
لم يعجبك أنني مريض في كثير من الأحيان
and brought her back to marry me in your place,
وأعدتها لتتزوجني بدلاً منك،
throwing yourself into Wanyan Jin's arms, didn't you?
ألقيتِ بنفسكِ بين ذراعي وانيان جين، أليس كذلك؟
At that time, I had my reason.
في ذلك الوقت، كان لديّ سببي.
What reason?
ما السبب؟
In truth, you were after his status, weren't you?
في الحقيقة، كنت تسعى وراء مكانته، أليس كذلك؟
So the one you loved was never me.
إذن، الشخص الذي أحببته لم أكن أنا أبداً.
All you cared about was power and status.
كل ما كنت تهتم به هو السلطة والمكانة.
Qi,
تشي،
I truly wanted to marry you.
كنت أرغب حقاً في الزواج منك.
At the time...
في ذلك الوقت...
It was Grandmother who opposed it.
كانت الجدة هي التي عارضت ذلك.
That's why she arranged for Su Qingran to be the substitute.
ولهذا السبب رتبت أن تكون سو تشينغران هي البديلة.
This was never my idea.
لم تكن هذه فكرتي أبداً.
If you had truly wanted to marry me,
لو كنتِ ترغبين حقاً في الزواج مني،
who could have stopped you?
من كان بإمكانه إيقافك؟
Su Feiyi,
سو فييي,
do you really think I am being toyed with in your hands,
هل تعتقد حقاً أنني أُتلاعب بي بين يديك؟
completely unaware of everything?
هل أنت جاهل تماماً بكل شيء؟
Help me one more time.
ساعدني مرة أخرى.
How else could I do?
ماذا كان بإمكاني أن أفعل غير ذلك؟
For you,
لك،
I gouged out Wen Yueqian's eyes,
لقد فقأت عيني وين يويتشيان،
ruined her face and thrown her off a cliff.
شوّه وجهها وألقى بها من أعلى جرف.
What about you?
ماذا عنك؟
How have you treated me?
كيف عاملتني؟
Wanyan Qi, oh Wanyan Qi,
وانيان تشي، أوه وانيان تشي،
stop pretending to be the innocent victim.
توقف عن التظاهر بأنك الضحية البريئة.
Back then, you treated Wen Yueqian that way,
في ذلك الوقت، كنت تعامل وين يويتشيان بتلك الطريقة.
because you were fickle and restless.
لأنك كنت متقلباً وقلقاً.
Now, you treat me like this
والآن، تعاملني هكذا
because you can't change who you are.
لأنك لا تستطيع تغيير من أنت.
Now that you have Su Qingran,
الآن وقد حصلت على سو تشينغران،
of course, you've forgotten me.
بالطبع، لقد نسيتني.
Don't talk nonsense.
لا تتفوه بالهراء.
Whether it's nonsense or not,
سواء كان ذلك هراءً أم لا،
you know the truth better than anyone.
أنت تعرف الحقيقة أفضل من أي شخص آخر.
Wanyan Qi, oh Wanyan Qi,
وانيان تشي، أوه وانيان تشي،
I don't hate you.
أنا لا أكرهك.
I pity you.
أنا أشفق عليك.
You've truly fallen for her.
لقد وقعت في حبها حقاً.
Just wait.
فقط انتظر.
Your reckoning is still to come.
لم يأتِ يوم الحساب بعد.
Su Feiyi, you are now the daughter of a disgraced official.
سو فييي، أنتِ الآن ابنة مسؤول مُدان.
Let's not discuss whether my father would agree or not;
دعونا لا نناقش ما إذا كان والدي سيوافق أم لا؛
even if you were to marry into my family,
حتى لو تزوجت من عائلتي،
with your status,
مع وضعك،
you're only fit to be a concubine.
أنتِ لا تصلحين إلا أن تكوني جارية.
A concubine?
محظية؟
Is she even worthy of marrying into our family?
هل هي جديرة بالزواج من عائلتنا؟
Why waste words on a lost dog?
لماذا نهدر الكلمات على كلب ضائع؟
Come with me to enjoy the plum blossoms.
تعال معي لنستمتع بأزهار البرقوق.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
You may leave now.
يمكنك المغادرة الآن.
Yes.
نعم.
Ran,
ران،
please save me.
من فضلك أنقذني.
♪In this world, who exactly♪
???في هذا العالم من بالضبط؟؟؟
♪Pushed me into the abyss?♪
???دفعني إلى الهاوية ؟؟؟؟
♪The sky is silent, and the sea says nothing♪
السماء صامتة، والبحر لا ينطق بكلمة.
♪Who shows me mercy in this world?♪
???من يرحمني في الدنيا؟؟؟؟
♪Cold winds sweep across the wasteland♪
???رياح باردة تكتسح الأرض القاحلة؟؟؟
♪Mercilessly gifting me snow and frost♪
???يمنحني الثلج والصقيع بلا رحمة؟؟؟
♪In this fleeting life♪
في هذه الحياة الزائلة
♪No mercy, no answers♪
لا رحمة، لا إجابات.
♪Yet one lamp shines, unafraid to go out♪
ومع ذلك فإن مصباحًا واحدًا يضيء، ولا يخاف من الانطفاء؟؟؟
♪Time can twist, but people aren't perfect♪
???قد يتغير الزمن، لكن الناس ليسوا كاملين؟؟؟
♪Who decides who comes and who parts?♪
???من يقرر من يأتي ومن يفارق ؟؟؟؟
♪It all rests on a single hopeful thought♪
كل شيء يعتمد على فكرة واحدة تبعث على الأمل.
♪Why fear one last breath?♪
لماذا الخوف من النفس الأخير؟
♪Love is brief, full of regrets♪
???الحب قصير، مليء بالندم؟؟؟
♪I paint the sky as a fan♪
???أرسم السماء كمروحة؟؟؟
♪To blow away nightmares and scatter the dust♪
???لإزالة الكوابيس وتبديد الغبار؟؟؟
♪Can't resist the fate of being separated♪
???لا تستطيع مقاومة مصير الانفصال؟؟؟
♪By distance♪
عن طريق المسافة
[Exclusive content rights reserved]
[جميع الحقوق محفوظة]
[by Youku Information Technology (Beijing) Co., Ltd.]
[من قبل شركة يوكو لتكنولوجيا المعلومات (بكين) المحدودة]